wooster.edu 2019-07-25

# Privacy Policy | The College of Wooster

Use of the website is subject to applicable federal and state laws, and for those to whom it applies, the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

When you use our websites, we may collect certain information. Here is an overview of the information we collect, how we use it, and how to contact us for more information. 

## Our Commitment to Privacy

A number of pages within Wooster-owned website properties contain links to external sites. When you leave one of our website properties, you are subject to the use and privacy policy of each new site you visit. 

If at any time we believe that your personal data has been compromised, we will immediately notify you and all other affected users. 

You may choose not to provide us with any personal information. You can still access/use most of our websites; however, you will not be able to access and use any part that requires such information. If you would like to change any information that you have submitted, please send your request to us at [webmaster@wooster.edu](mailto:webmaster@wooster.edu). 

## The Information We Collect

**Personal Information:**  We collect information that can be used to identify you as an individual ("Personally Identifiable Information," or PII) only when you provide this information directly to us, such as voluntarily submitting a form or signing up for an email list. You do not have to provide any PII to use our websites; however, if you submit a form on our site, we may store the information we collect through that form. We may also collect information through your voluntary interaction with any of our public forums, including our social media platforms. Depending on the purpose for providing your PII, it may or may not be discarded (see our [GDPR Privacy Statement](https://wiki.wooster.edu/display/itdocumentation/GDPR+Privacy+Statement)). 

**Google Analytics:**  We use a variety of Google Analytics tools to gather information about how you use our websites and the devices you use to access them, such as your IP address, geographical location, length of visit, pages viewed, and browser preferences. We use this information to better understand site usage and to make improvements to the user experience. We will never (and will not allow any third-party to) use Google Analytics to track or to collect any PII of visitors to our sites. Google offers an [opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) that provides visitors the ability to prevent Google Analytics from using their data. 

**Cookies:**  As you browse our websites, cookies (small files of basic information) may be placed on your computer so that we can learn more about how you arrived at our site and whether you've visited previously. We may also use cookies to prefill forms with your contact information and to target advertising to you when you're on other external websites. You may choose not to accept cookies from our sites. Please refer to your specific browser for information on opting out or deleting cookies. 

## How We Use Your Information

  * Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA): Please be advised that any time a user enters information, we will assume that the user is 13 or older. 
  * Confidentiality: All personal information shared with us remains confidential. We do not share, sell, or rent your contact information to any third-party. 
  * Communications: We may use PII you provide to us to communicate with you about our programs, events, and other news at The College of Wooster. 

All updates to this policy will be posted on this page. The "last updated" date reflects the date of the most recent change. 

## Contact Us

For more information about our privacy policy, please email us at [webmaster@wooster.edu](mailto:webmaster@wooster.edu). 

Last updated: 05-24-18
